Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of the Washington Square News RG.39.178
New York University Archives
New York University Archives Collection of the Washington Square News
1973-2025
New York University Archives
Washington Square News
RG.39.178
90.50 Linear Feet in 53 oversize flat boxes, 9 reels of microfilm, 51 bound volumes, and 3 folders in shared housing
3 websites in 3 archived websites.
This collection contains issues from the student newspaper the Washington Square News (established as the Washington Square Daily News), dating from 1973 to 2025. This newspaper documents life at NYU, local and national news, campus living, and student clubs. The collection is extensive but not comprehensive, there may be some issues that were published but are not included in this collection. This collection includes issues in their original print format as well as microfilmed copies. Some issues are bound.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
In 2013, https://nyunews.com/ was selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
In May 2020, https://issuu.com/nyu.news/docs/wywh/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2020.040. In September 2021, https://issuu.com/nyu.news/docs/wywh_2021/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.009.
In December 2023 and May 2024, two accretions were donated by Nanci Healy. The accession numbers associated with these transfers are 2024.023 and 2024.046.
In May 2025, an accretion of Under the Arch magazines from Spring 2025 were added to this collection. There is no information about the provenance of these materials, but they were likely acquired through distribution. The accession number associated with this accretion is 2025.024.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Arrangement
Newspapers are arranged chronologically.
Historical Note
New York University has had many student newspapers with many different names since its founding. The Heights campus and the Washington Square campus had separate student newspapers until 1973 when the Heights campus was closed. The Washington Square News was first published in the fall of 1973, and was preceded by the Washington Square Journal.
Originally titled the Washington Square Daily News, the newspaper shortened its title in the fall of 1974 and continues to be distributed/circulated.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Researchers must consult microfilm copies for issues published between 1973 and 1987 due to the fragility of the original newspapers.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains issues from the student newspaper the Washington Square News (established as the Washington Square Daily News), dating from 1973 to 2025. This newspaper documents life at NYU, local and national news, campus living, and student clubs. This collection also contains Washington Square News's arts and culture publication, The Village Angle Magazine, dating from 1983 to 1988. The collection is extensive but not comprehensive, there may be some issues that were published but are not included in this collection. This collection includes issues in their original print format as well as microfilmed copies. Some issues are bound. The collection also includes the website for the publication, with crawls of the website dating back to 2013.
College student newspapers and periodicals.; Student activities.; Washington square news (New York, N.Y.)
- Microfilm copies
  - Washington Square Daily News, September 1973-May 1974 (Box Shared University Archives 105, Reel 5056)
  - Washington Square News, September 1974-May 1976 (Box Shared University Archives 105, Reel 5057)
  - Washington Square News, September 1976-May 1978 (Box Shared University Archives 105, Reel 5058)
  - Washington Square News, September 1978-May 1980 (Box Shared University Archives 105, Reel 5059)
  - Washington Square News, September 1980-May 1982 (Box Shared University Archives 105, Reel 5060)
  - Washington Square News, September 1982-April 1984 (Box Shared University Archives 105, Reel 5061)
  - Washington Square News, September 1984-May 1986 (Box Shared University Archives 105, Reel 5062)
  - Washington Square News, 1986-1987 (Box Shared University Archives 102)
  - Washington Square News, Summer 1987 (Box Shared University Archives 102, Reel 8106)
- Print copies
  - Washington Square News, April 29, 1987-November 4, 1987 (Box 12)
  - Washington Square News, November 4, 1987-April 25, 1988 (Box 13)
  - Washington Square News, March 19, 1991-November 11, 1991 (Box 19)
  - Washington Square News, November 13, 1991-May 4, 1992 (Box 20)
  - Washington Square News, August 31, 1992-October 5, 1993 (Box 21)
  - Washington Square News, November 24, 2003-April 26, 2004, April 4, 2013, January 26, 2015-March 11, 2015 (Box 37)
  - Washington Square News, August - November 2004 (Box 51, Folder 1-6)
  - Washington Square News, December 2004 - March 2005 (Box 52, Folder 1-6)
  - Washington Square News, April-June 2005, August-October 1, 2006 (Box 53, Folder 1-5)
  - Washington Square News, October 2-December 10, 2006 (Box 54, Folder 1-6)
  - Washington Square News, January 16-March 29, 2007 (Box 55, Folder 1-5)
  - Washington Square News, April 2-June, 2007; August 26-October 26, 2012 (Box 56, Folder 1-7)
  - Washington Square News, November 5-December 13, 2012; January 27-February 27, 2014 (Box 57, Folder 1-5)
  - Washington Square News, March 3-September 29, 2014 (Box 58, Folder 1-6)
  - Washington Square News, October 1, 2014 - March 12, 2015 (Box 59, Folder 1-7)
  - Washington Square News, March 23-December 10, 2015 (Box 60, Folder 1-7)
  - Washington Square News, March 12, 2015-January 25, 2016 (Box 38)
  - Washington Square News, February 1, 2016-May 9, 2017 (Box 39)
  - Washington Square News, Spring 2024 (Box Shared University Archives 149, Folder 18)
  - Under the Arch Magazine, Spring 2025 (Box Shared University Archives 156, Folder 8, Box Shared University Archives 157, Folder 2)
- Bound print copies
  - Washington Square News, September 16, 1980-May 13, 1981 (Box 50)
  - Washington Square News, September 12, 1988-December 12, 1988 (Volume September-December 1988)
  - Washington Square News, September 6, 1989-November 8, 1989 (Volume September-November 1989)
  - Washington Square News, January 24, 1990-April 25, 1990 (Volume January-April 1990)
  - Washington Square News, September 4, 1990-December 12, 1990 (Volume September-December 1990)
  - Washington Square News, January 24, 1991-May 3, 1991 (Volume January-May 1991)
  - Washington Square News, January 28, 1992-April 27, 1992 (Volume January-April 1992)
  - Washington Square News, February 4, 1993-April 28, 1993 (Volume February-April 1993)
  - Washington Square News, August 30, 1993-December 14, 1993 (Volume August-December 1993)
  - Washington Square News, January 20, 1994-April 28, 1994 (Volume January-April 1994)
  - Washington Square News (2 copies), September 1, 1994-December 12, 1994 (Volume September-December 1994, Volume September-December 1994 Copy 2)
  - Washington Square News (2 copies), January 23, 1995-May 18, 1995 (Volume January-May 1995, Volume January-May 1995 Copy 2)
  - Washington Square News, August 31, 1995-December 11, 1995 (Volume August-December 1995)
  - Washington Square News (2 copies), January 22, 1996-May 16, 1996 (Volume January-May 1996)
  - Washington Square News, September 4, 1996-December 11, 1996 (Volume September-December 1996)
  - Washington Square News, January 23, 1997-May 15, 1997 (Volume January-May 1997)
  - Washington Square News, August 26, 1997-December 10, 1997 (Volume August-December 1997)
  - Washington Square News, January 21, 1998-May 14, 1998 (Volume January-May 1998)
  - Washington Square News, August 31, 1998-December 13, 1998 (Volume August-December 1998)
  - Washington Square News, Jan. 20, 1999-May 13, 1999 (Volume January-May 1999)
  - Washington Square News, Aug. 30, 1999-Dec. 10, 1999 (Volume August-December 1999)
  - Washington Square News, January 19, 2000-April 30, 2000 (Volume January-April 2000)
  - Washington Square News, Aug. 28, 2000-Dec. 10, 2000 (Volume August-December 2000)
  - Washington Square News, Jan. 17, 2001-May 9, 2001 (Volume January-May 2001)
  - Washington Square News, August 27, 2001-December 9, 2001 (Volume August-December 2001)
  - Washington Square News, Jan. 23, 2002-May 13, 2002 (Volume January-May 2002)
  - Washington Square News, Aug. 26, 2002-Dec. 6, 2002 (Volume August-December 2002)
  - Washington Square News, Jan. 22, 2003-June 30, 2003 (Volume January-June 2003)
  - Washington Square News, August 25, 2003-December 5, 2003 (Volume August-December 2003)
  - Washington Square News, January 21, 2004-June 28, 2004 (Volume January-June 2004)
  - Washington Square News, August 30, 2005-December 9, 2005 (Volume August-December 2005)
  - Washington Square News, Jan. 17, 2006-June 26, 2006 (Volume January-June 2006)
  - Washington Square News (2 copies), August 27, 2007-December 7, 2007 (Volume August-December 2007, Volume August-December 2007 Copy 2)
  - Washington Square News (2 copies), January 22, 2008-June 30, 2008 (Volume January-June 2008, Volume January-June 2008 Copy 2)
  - Washington Square News, Fall 2008 (Volume Fall 2008)
  - Washington Square News, Fall 2009 (Volume Fall 2009)
  - Washington Square News, Spring 2009 (Volume Spring 2009)
  - Washington Square News, Fall 2010 (Volume Fall 2010)
  - Washington Square News, Spring 2010 (Volume Spring 2010)
  - Washington Square News, Fall 2011 (Volume Fall 2011)
  - Washington Square News (2 copies), Spring 2011 (Volume Spring 2011, Volume Spring 2011 Copy 2)
  - Washington Square News, Spring 2012 (Volume Spring 2012)
  - Washington Square News (2 copies), Fall 2013 (Volume Fall 2013, Volume Fall 2013 Copy 2)
- Archived Websites, October 2013-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Accruals
  In general, the Washington Square News website was accrued quarterly. In 2020, crawling was increased to weekly. In September 2020, accruals were changed to monthly.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Issuu publications are currently not playable in Wayback.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of nyunews.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints. Facebook was blocked. Website was rescoped to attempt to capture issuu publications linked to the website.
  Scope and Contents
  The Washington Square News has been captured since 2013. There is a gap in capture of the website from 2016-2017. The website provides daily news to readers around NYU's Manhattan and Brooklyn campuses, Greenwich Village, Brooklyn Heights, and NYU's global campuses. The website offers news, culture, arts, editorial, sports coverage, photos and videos from around campus and New York City, in conjunction with the magazine, Under the Arch. In September 2020, the staff resigned from the newspaper. New articles were not added to the website until the Spring 2021 semester.
  The crawls also include a capture of While You Were Here 2020, an annual magazine directed to seniors recapping their four years at NYU.
- The Village Angle Magazine
  The Village Angle was an arts and culture magazine published by the Washington Square News in the 1980s.
  - The Village Angle Magazine, February 23, 1983-May 16, 1988 (Box 42)